A Finding Aid to the Louis Pomerantz Papers, 1937-1988, bulk 1950s-1988, in the Archives of American Art aaa.pomeloui
Archives of American Art
- Writings and Notes, 1950s-1980s; Series 4; 2.8 Linear feet Box 7
  Also found is a portfolio of copies of Pomerantz's writings from 1962-1978, and Pomerantz's notebook from the Rijksmuseum which includes notes and hand-colored sketches on conservation techniques, as well as photographs of Pomerantz conducting conservation work.
  The series contains sound recordings of circa 11 lectures and presentations on 10 sound tape reels and 10 sound cassettes.
  - Courses for Campbell Center for Historic Preservation Studies, 1950s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Courses for Campbell Center for Historic Preservation Studies: "Care and Preservation of Paintings", 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
  - Lectures, Meetings and Seminars, 1950s-1980s; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Lecture Notes, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Outlines, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Lecture Outline, Conservation (Advanced Museum Techniques Course), circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lectures Pending, 1960s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lectures/Papers (Box 5)
    - "A Standard for Recording Angle of Light in Photography", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "An Inexpensive Infrared Video Viewing System", 1982 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Art Consumption: To Escalate or Control?", 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - "Art Forgeries, Copies and Detection", 1970s (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - "Care of a Painting Collection", 1970s; Includes 1 sound cassette and 3 sound tape reels (Box 5, Folder 12-15)
    - "Caring for Works of Art on Paper", 1980s (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "Comments by a Conservator on Contemporary Painting Conservation", 1961 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Concise Reporting of the Condition of Paintings", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Conservation Techniques For/On Works of Art", 1970s; Includes 1 sound tape reel of presentation at the Mountain Plains Museum Conference in 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
    - "Conservators Advise Artists", 1970s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Detection of Fakes and Forgeries in Works of Art", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "El Greco's Assumption of the Virgin (My Favorite Painting at the Art Institute of Chicago)", circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Ethics and Philosophy", 1977; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Ethics, Taste, Facts, Fancy: Specific Concerns of Conservators", 1980s (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Field Museum's 24-Piece Gamelan: Examination and Treatment", 1980s (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "First Steps in Conservation Training", 1980s (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "General Outline of Examination and Treatment Procedures," Original, circa 1980s (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Handouts for University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "Health and Safety Hazards in Art Conservation", 1981; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Inherent Vice", 1970s (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "Is it Genuine? A Conservator of Paintings Faces This Question", 1970s; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - "Know What You See", 1970s; 2 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - "Know What You See: The Examination of Paintings by Photo-Optical Techniques", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Learning to See", circa 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Lining Treatment of a Northwest Coast Indian Cedar Mat (Makah Tribe)", 1970s; Includes 1 sound cassette (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Marks of a Professional Conservator", 1980s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "On the Immorality of Faulty Craftsmanship", circa 1960s; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - On X-Rays of Paintings, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Paintings: A Method of Mounting on a Rigid Support", 1970s (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - "Preventive Care of Paintings: What to Do About It", 1970s (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Problems in the Conservation of Contemporary Paintings", 1961; 1 sound tape reels (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Restoration and Conservation of Paintings in the Israel Museum (UNESCO report), 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Role of the Conservator in Advising Artists", 1980; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "Scientific Aids in Conservation" delivered to Argonne Branch of RESA, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "Specifications Regarding Packing of Paintings for Shipment", 1960s (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Talk to Delta Phi Delta, Fullerton Hall, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Truth in Seeing", 1970s; Includes 1 sound tape reel (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
    - "What to Look for Before Shipping the Painting", circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Your Contemporary Painting May Be More Temporary Than You Think", 1961; Includes 1 sound tape reel (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
  - List of Slides Used in Lectures, 1960s-1970s (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Notes, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Notes, Cleaning Paintings, circa 1970s (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Notes, Mural Paintings, Causes of Deterioration, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Notes, Silica Gel for Micro Climate, 1980s (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Portfolio of Writings from 1962-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Rijksmuseum Notebook, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 4-8)
- Project/Client Files, 1950s-1987; Series 5; 13.8 Linear feet Boxes 7-20 (Box 7, Folder 9-12)
  Project/Client Files document Pomerantz's conservation on artwork for individuals, museums, institutions, and private companies. Files typically include preliminary condition reports and recommendations for treatment; agreement and release forms authorizing treatment; receipts for financial transactions, related correspondence, and in some cases photographic material.
  Series includes files for clients for whom Pomerantz did a large volume of conservation work including Leigh Block, Chicago Board of Trade, Nathan Cummings, Edgar W. Garbisch, Nelson Harris, Jerome Hill, International Minerals and Chemical Corporation, Arnold H. Maremont, Milwaukee Art Museum, Ohio Historical Society, United States Postal Service, University of Iowa Museum of Art, and the Wichita Art Museum Ronald P. Murdock Collection.
  Art Institute of Chicago files are relatively extensive and include records documenting conservation department activities, committees and budgets, in addition to individual projects conducted by the Institute's conservation department.
  Also found here are extensive files documenting Pomerantz's work on the Gamelan collection at the Field Museum of Natural History, including condition reports, background and research material, sound recordings, photographs, and news clippings.
  A group of folders at the end of the series documents client projects that remained unfinished when Pomerantz died in 1988.
  The series includes 2 sound recordings related to an exhibition on 2 sound tape reels.
  - Abbott Laboratories, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
  - Abbott Laboratories, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Adams, Patricia, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Adele Rosenberg Gallery, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Adler Planetarium, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Albert R. Lee & Co., Inc., 1950s-1961 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Alschuler, J. E., 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - American National Bank and Trust Company of Chicago, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Anderson, Alice (Mrs. Arthur M.), 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Anderson, Gail V., 1981 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Anderson, Lee, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - American Federation of Art, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Anderson, Nancy, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Anheuser-Busch, Inc., 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Arenberg, Albert L., 1950s-1970s (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Arizona Historical Society, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Armour, Philip D., 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Arondean Art Gallery, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Aronson, Lawrence, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Art Institute of Chicago (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Committees, Trustees and Women's Board, 1955-1965 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Conservation Department Summary of Activities, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1961 (Box 7, Folder 33-41)
    - Examination Reports, 1954-1961 (Box 7, Folder 42-43)
    - Expense Statements, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Publicity, 1955-1965 (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
    - Receipts, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Resignation, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
    - Rubens Adoration of the Magi, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Seurat La Grande Jatte Move, 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Art: USA: Now (Messing, Joseph B.), 1960s (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Arts Club of Chicago, 1962-1966 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Atwater, A. G., 1960s (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Axtell, Louise, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bader, Alfred, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Badonsky, George, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Baer, Richard, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Bak, Mrs. Alexander, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Baker, Mrs. Donald, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Ball State University, 1967-1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Barlas, Joan and Kosta, 1960s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
  - Barrett Wendell, Robert, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Bass, Bill, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Baumgarten, Dodie, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Baxter, Mrs., circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Bee Paper Company, Inc., 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Bender, H. W., Jr., circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Bensinger, B. E., 1960s (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Bensinger, Robert F., 1967-1969 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Bentley, Claude, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Benton, Charles, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 33-36)
  - Bergman, Edwin A., 1959-1960s (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Berkson, Doris, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Berman, Julian L., 1977 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Bernard Horwich Jewish Community Center, 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Beveridge, Mrs. Albert J., 1959 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Bierig, Henry J., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Bishop Hill Heritage Assn., Inc. (Ronald Nelson), 1960s (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Blackburn, Thomas, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Block, Leigh B., 1957-1971 (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
  - Boe, John, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Boisonnas, Alain G., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Bolz, Eugenie M., 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Boyd, Mary, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Bradley, Mr. and Mrs. Harry Lynde, 1960s-1980s (Box 8, Folder 51-55)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bryan, Charles A., circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Burden, Shirley C., 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Butler, Gerald, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cancilla, Dr. Pasquela, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Carel, William, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Carter, Bernard, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Carter, Ledyard & Milburn, circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Carton, Dr. and Mrs Robert, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Chaffee, Donna, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Academy of Sciences, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Board of Trade, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 12-24)
  - Chicago Historical Society, 1950s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1950s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Christenson, Keith A., 1981 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Church of Saint Mary of the Assumption, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 28-30)
  - Clark, Mary, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Clark, Virginia Fairfield, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Clifford, John S., 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Clowes Fund, Incorporated, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Cohen, Elizabeth, circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Cohen, George M., 1970s (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Comar, Jerome M., 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Conklin, Leahy and Eisenberg, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Container Corporation of America (Carol Lipper), 1960s (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Contemporary Arts Center, 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Continental Bank, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Corbino, Mrs. Jon, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Culberg, Ruth, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cummings, Nathan, 1950s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
  - Cummings, Willard, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - D'Agnese, Irene, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Davidheiser, Lois, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Dayton's Gallery 12, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - De Costa, Alyce and Edwin J., 1978 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - De Witt Bros., circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Debevoise, Mrs. Thomas, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Deere & Company, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Deering, Donald W., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Delaware Art Museum, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Demouth, Mary Louise, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Des Moines Art Center, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Deson-Zaks Gallery, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Detroit Athletic Club, 1976-1979 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Devenberg, Susan, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Dewey Community Conference, 1971-1977 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Dickes, Dr., 1950s (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Dimond, Mrs. Seymour A, Estate of Pierce Rosenberg, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Dolnick, Mr. and Mrs. Lee, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Donnelley, Robert, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Donner, Joan, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Dorlands, 1960-1961 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Dow & Stonebridge, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Downtown Gallery, 1952-1970 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Dwight, Edward H. (Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute), 1962-1978 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Dytch, Meredith M., 1979 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Edelstone, Sigmund, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Elsse's Ceramics, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Emmerich, 1950s (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Eppenstein, Louise K., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Epstein, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Epstein, Julius, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Evanston Historical Society, 1966-1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Evansville Museum of Arts and Sciences, 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Fagen, Abel E., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Fairchild, Mrs., circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Fairweather Hardin Gallery, 1956-1979 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Federal Insurance Co., 1971-1978 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Feinberg, Bernard, 1960s (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Feldt, Irene, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Ferguson, Dr. J. E., 1978-1980 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Field, Mrs. E. S., 1950s (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Field Museum of Natural History, 1960s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 49-60)
  - Field Museum of Natural History, 1960s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 1-6)
  - Field Museum of Natural History, Photographic Material, 1960s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
  - Field Museum of Natural History, Sound Recordings, 1960s-1980s; 9 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 11-13)
  - First National Bank of Chicago, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - First Unitarian Church of Milwaukee, 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Fisher, Mr. and Mrs. Richard, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Flagg, Richard B., 1978 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Fleischman, Lawrence A., 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 18-19)
  - Florsheim, Harold and Sue, 1958-1979 (Box 11, Folder 20-21)
  - Florsheim, Lillian H., 1961-1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Forman, Dr. Irving and Natalie, 1964-1971 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Foundation Historical Association, Inc., 1953-1955 (Box 11, Folder 24-25)
  - Fox, Roderick and Carolyn, 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Frank, Mrs. Arthur J., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Frank B. Cartwright & Associates, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Frank E. Donkin & Company, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Freeman, Lee, 1970s (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Freeman, Lee, Jr., 1970-1985 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Friedman, Frances R., circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Friedman, Roy J., 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Funk & Wagnalls Co., circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Gable, Robert E., 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Garbisch, Edgar W., 1950s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 36-39)
  - Garbisch, Edgar W., 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Gavin, Louise and Norman, 1960s (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Gaynor, Rev. James G., 1983 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Geist, Jack, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - General Adjustment Bureau, 1961-1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - General Casualty Company of Wisconsin, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - George F. Harding Museum, 1960s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
  - Gethsemane Women's Guild, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Getz, James, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Gidwitz, Adele and Willard, 1960s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
  - Gilson, Warren E., 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Glore, Mrs Charles, 1956-1961 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Godwin, Francis B., circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Gothard, Harry, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Graff, Everett D., 1940-1981 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Grahn, Douglas, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Greear, John A., 1960 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Green, Bernice, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Greenfield Village and Henry Ford Museum, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Griffith, Mr. and Mrs. Dean L., 1980s (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Grober, Sam, 1980s (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Grund, David, Astro Art Ltd., 1970s (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Gulbeck, Per E., 1972-1979 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Gustafson, David, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Gutnayer, J. Marion, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Hadassy, Efraim, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Hadley-Rollin, 1950s (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Hagerty, Julia M., 1975 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Halfen, David, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Hallen, Eric A., 1979-1985 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Hamilton, Juan, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Hanck, Nancy, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Hansen, Frederick F., 1985 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Hardigg, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Harding, John, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Harding Museum, circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Harris, Nelson, 1960s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 44-46)
  - Harris, Rev. Thomas G., 1960s-1980s (Box 12, Folder 47-48)
  - Harris Trust and Savings Bank, 1960-1981 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Hay, Richard, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Hayes, Albert M., 1959-1976 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Haynes, Mrs. R. B., 1950s (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Hayward, John, 1962-1965 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Henderson, Mr. and Mrs. William J., 1975-1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Henkle, John (John Crearer Library), 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Herbert H. Kohl Charities, Inc., 1976-1986 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Herrold, Lloyd, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hill, Jerome, 1950s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 6-10)
  - Hill, Louis W., Jr., 1950s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Himmel, Richard, 1969-1973 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Hirsch, Mr. and Mrs. Hilton, 1962-1976 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Hirschmann, Jerome, 1969-1985 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Hirschoeck, Herbert C., 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Hispanic Society of America, 1951-1964 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Hokin, Mr. and Mrs. Edwin, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Holland, Frank, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Hollander, Dr. and Mrs. Alexander, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Hoopes, Thomas T., 1963 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Hoover, E. Earl, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Horn, Milton, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Horner, Frank, 1960s-1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Howell, Douglas, 1961-1965 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Hunt, Leithner & Co., Inc. (Adele Rosenbeg Gallery), 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Hunt, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Hutchings, Sue Austin, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Inland Steel Company, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - International College of Surgeons, 1959-1974 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - International Minerals and Chemical Corporation, 1960s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 30-35)
  - Isaacson, Jim, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Ives, Timothy R, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - J. K. Smit & Sons, Inc., 1950s (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Jacques Baruch Gallery, 1978-1980 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - James Lodge & Associates, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Janesville Art League, 1930s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Jellnick, Roy and Miller, Graham, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Jesmer, Robert, 1970s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 43-44)
  - Joffee, Mrs. Norman, 1973-1974 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - John Crear Library, 1960s (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - John Herron Art Institute, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - John Russell Mitchell Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Johnson Foundation, 1970s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Joliet Township High School, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Jones, Dan Burne, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Jones, Gordon R., 1983 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Karger, Mrs. Frank Jr., 1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Kaufman, Barbara, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Kaufman, Xavier, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Keating, Arthur, 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Kenly, Granger, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Kent, Sheldon E., 1980s (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - King, Charles G., 1982 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Klein, Carolyn, circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Knickerbocker, D. G., 1950s (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Kohl, Herbert H., 1978 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Kohl, Sidney, 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
  - Kootz Gallery, 1950s (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Kootz, Samuel M., 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Kozlosky, Charles and Martha, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Krausen, Anthony and Nicole, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Kraushaar Galleries, 1954-1956 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Krubeck, Mr. and Mrs. Ralph D., 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Kunstadter, Sigmund, 1950s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Lachner, Mrs. J. C., 1960 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Lafferty, Joseph S., 1975 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Lane, Sam, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Lawrence University, 1950s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Legg, Alicia, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Leistner, Dr. and Mrs., circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Levinson, William, 1980s (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Linard, Henri, 1959-1966 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Little Gallery, Inc., 1972 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Llewellyn, Mrs. J. T., 1968 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Lord, Day & Lord, 1953-1954 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Louer, Mrs. Albert E. M., 1980s (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Loyola University (Donald F. Rowe), 1960s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Ludgin, Earle, 1950s (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - MacAllister, Paul, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Madison Art Center, 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Mann, Gertrude, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Maremont, Arnold H., 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 40-50)
  - Maremont, Arnold H., 1960s-1970s (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Mark, Gordon, 1970s (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Marquette University, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Marshall Field & Company, 1982-1985 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Marty, Helen, Estate of, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Marxer & Company, 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Mary & Leigh Block Gallery, Northwestern University, 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 57-58)
  - Mayer, Karl, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Mayer, Robert B., 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Mayo Clinic, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Chauncey, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - McCormick Place Art Gallery, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - McCracken, Lynda, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - McCulloch, Mrs. Hugh B., 1965-1967 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - McKey & Poague, Inc., 1950s (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - McMahnon, Marion, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - McNear, Everett, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - McWilliams, James D., 1980s (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Means, Duane E., 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Melamed, Abraham and Hope, 1960s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Merchandise Mart, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Met-L Wood Corporation, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 16-17)
  - Micheels, A. H., 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Mignin, Kathy and Robert, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Miller, Carla M. and Donald O., 1980s (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Miller, Frank J., 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Miller, Lucia and Harry, 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 22-23)
  - Miller, Nancy, 1970s (Box 15, Folder 24)